i don't know what i did to upset you
but i don't think i deserve this
stop it
no
stop it so the reason that i've got a
llama spitting at me at the moment is
because i found probably one of the best
wandering traders
ever and to stop him despawning do you
mind stop it
to stop him despawning i had to very
quickly hastily rename him so i grabbed
a name tag and i
and he's gone
just like that and he's back
and his name for some reason my
quick typing hand came up with drefu a
bit of a weird name but check it out
i've already bought all of the hermit
heads that he's had to offer not too bad
we'll get some of those
polish black stone not too bad
oak planks
then i scrolled down and found
not only
diamond block one of the most valuable
mini blocks but also shulker box look at
that so i'm gonna try and trade up as
many of these as possible but check it
out these are all the mini blocks we got
from that single trader which is amazing
i think we ought to sell these
separately but why does this matter
well it matters because
we lost
almost all our diamonds playing iskall's
mini-game
i used
over half of the profits from the barge
this was a stack of diamonds gone we've
we've got to get it back so steadily i'm
going to restock everything and make it
a little more enticing to buy some stuff
from the barge i have prepared
more boxes for the mystery box and since
we got sold out apart from one i'm going
to add another one into the mix this
time it will be held
by our good friend
pesky bird
now the question is
will people choose the pesky bird
because he's different
or will they stay away as a warning well
as always i'm not going to tell you i'm
going to mix up all these boxes and
randomly place them and then people can
make their decision which green they're
going to take or the pesky bird so this
is the naf barge box this is the one
that didn't get sold it still has an
ancient debris in there so it's it's
still kind of worth it but i've added a
not bad box so it's got a bit of
everything a couple of shulker boxes
lots of gold
golden carrots that's that's probably
the new new naf box to be honest and
then you got pretty good box bro it's
got some name tags more shulkers
emeralds and another right shovel and
then you've got whoa
smashing box this one is a really good
one you've got a whole nether right inga
netherright pick
eight shulker boxes and ender chest
galore so there's some really good
prizes to be won out of these boxes
so i'm gonna mix these up you'll never
know which way they go
right no one knows which box is which
this should get me some diamonds back my
goal this episode is to get back where i
was that means a full stack of diamond
blocks that's pretty that's pretty heavy
and i'm not gonna get it just from the
mystery boxes either i'm gonna have to
do
dare i say it
some mining
i don't really want to have to but i had
plans for those diamonds and now it's
kind of ruined because of my
horrible addiction
to the the shovels over at iskall's
treasure hunt so i'm sure the barge can
make some profits and
whoa whoa whoa
what is going on here
hep agent
hermitcraft environmental
protection agent
hrp
hermitcraft
rad person
what is that hermitcraft why are they
from different organizations
this could mean anything
hermit real pointer hermit regular
person
it could literally mean anything what
does hrp stand for
go nuts in the comments
right the mycelium resistance has been
found and quarantined i love this this
is really cool it looks like they're
extracting the mycelium
i haven't got any more
you can't stop the resistance gonna
sneak it's gonna sneak out of the
quarantine there's not a lot you can do
to stop the mycelium spreading
it's going to get very quickly out of
hand and it's like pouring over this
there is nothing that they can do and
what about the other patch that i made
oh my goodness there's another one
stay back
burn it all i agree there's like a
full-on
philo there is a full-on there's a
full-on removal operation going on it's
spreading and there's nothing you can do
one thing i could do is place dirt and
let the myceliums and the the grass kind
of naturally fight it out see which one
makes it in
of course the chances are that it's
mostly going to be
the grass because it's surrounded by it
more let's put yourself here and see
what happens
yeah it doesn't look like
the resistance is doing well we might
need to give it a little more help well
i gave it i gave it a chance i gave it a
go it didn't work so we'll just build it
up even more and we'll leave a calling
card for our very own
mayor of the shopping district why did i
make this a two block center because now
it has to be one side of the other
leave that there so let's actually get
some work done now
we need to make some progress and the
first thing i want to do
is get my upside down mansion spawn
proof back to the upside down we go what
in blue blazers is going on here there's
an upside down rocket machine scars are
mad man and it's it's not even connected
it's nice to see some development here
actually this will be a really nice
place once we will get going so the
interior of the mansion something i
didn't really think about getting to
so i think this is the perfect
opportunity for a grind lapse where
we're going to remove this and get this
place properly spawn proofed now if my
unintentional mob farm works
this guy should have a bunch of gold on
him
yep
he does so
let's just crack let's just crack on
shall we
get started
[Music]
it may not have been the most majestic
or
the most marvelous of time lapses but
this is the sort of work that makes
hermit craft what it is
boring repetitive block placement i had
to tidy up this interior it just had to
be done i've had a word with b dubs off
camera and he is on board with the
project and very very much excited
i'm sick of carpet
i think i spent about three hours just
getting this place mostly spawn proof
i've definitely forgotten some places
yep look hit right here immediately
already forgotten but it's mostly spawn
proof look there's barely any pigmen
here there's definitely none in here i
think we've done a pretty good job and
they're there these guys might actually
be holding gold
yeah they were all holding items
so that is one of the jobs ticked off my
to-do list for today
oh i'm so sick of these guys you two
tasks dead-eyed leather dropping
pig
that's what they are and it's line ball
all of that to try and get rid of the
piglens
and they still spawn occasionally it's
gonna be it's gonna be a long road to
getting this place completely safe and
in fact some of these shulker boxes were
actually destined for the barge the plan
is really really simple i want to break
through the bedrock
right about here roughly the same place
that i was before i want to break a big
hole in the middle and have the piglin
farm or the zombie piglen farm above
here and i still want them to fall down
this is going to be a really cool
project once we get going and i'm so
thankful that p-tubs is here to help
because i must admit this this project
is turning into a little bit of a chore
so now we're gonna head back to the
mansion this is why we need a magic
fireplace so we can get back here
quicker we're gonna drop we're gonna
drop off all of the carrots and head
back to the mansion
so now what i really need to do is kind
of grip my teeth
and go and farm well not farm mine i
wish you could farm diamonds we need to
go and mine some diamonds and i don't
actually have a proper mine in my base
at all
i just have
well i guess i'd have the one over there
with scar but
this is not going to be fun
hermit oh my goodness
hermit challenge herm hermit challenge
challenge challengers
challengers target hermit challenges
hermit
target
they're just giving me a box of junk
wait no this is my box of junk am i
missing something i am 100 missing
something here i was i thought this was
a box that they gave me i'm guessing
this is mumbo and
possibly
iskall because they're the ones that are
in charge of
hermit challenges
i feel like i'm potentially missing
something either way let's focus on the
task at hand
we need to go
and get ourselves some diamonds and
unfortunately the best way to do that
is to just mine it
so we're gonna do a small mining session
to see if we can get
some of our money back that iskall has
taken well not he didn't take it but i
lost to isk
do you see
okay
it wasn't it wasn't it wasn't herman
challenger's
ahead it had nothing to do with this
shulker box
there's something up here isn't there
there's a there's a giant
there's a giant parrot
how old
that was that there that literally was
that there the whole time
oh that's so embarrassing
i really hope i'm gonna have to watch
that footage back
and check if that was just hanging there
or if i genuinely could have missed it
that's so embarrassing there i i've i i
must have cut out about two minutes of
me reopening this shulker box being
confused but that was just a giant
parrot
and a target block there oh
hermit challenges target that's the
target
what is up here anything that i should
be worried about
it is well it's a proper it's a proper
parrot it that there is a proper parrot
right i feel like we got to do this
properly let's have no spoilers let's
get ourselves some arrows this is the
most exciting thing that's appeared in
my base all season we're gonna do it
properly we're not gonna tamper with it
in any way i wonder if a rocket will
work
oh it did
[Laughter]
well that brings back memories
oops i killed oh i killed one
oh no
oh wait
oh they're all renamed
oh no
this was really important and i killed
one
uh-oh
we'll uh pretend that that didn't happen
what do i do with this information
okay what do they say what do they say
uh do a one minute dance montage
what have a breakdown in episode 44
randomly start
complaining in chat oh no these are all
challenges
in the form of chickens oh no oh no okay
well the first thing i'm going to do is
stop these guys leaving
i don't want i don't want to yeah
they're already they're already leaving
oh no how do i i don't know how to
process this information right now let's
let's get them
nice and safe
we don't want any chickens leaving
my base there's already two that are on
the move
they are they're so smart what are you
doing
they're all making a break for it right
the wall's going here instead
no
they are desperate to escape can you be
honest with me everyone does anybody can
anybody honestly raise their hand and
say i know how hermit challenges works
because i can't i cannot raise my hand
and say i know what's going on i haven't
even finished stealing everyone's doors
okay so i guess what we do
take these a couple at a time i can't do
all of these in one go
uh
give this chicken a purpose
right well um i think that's gonna be
the first one on the list
well i think oh which which one was he
i'm not gonna read all of these i kind
of want them to be a surprise over time
kill this chicken well i could do that
one
you couldn't have been the one that i
threw a trident at could you i had i've
eliminated a real challenge right
challenge accepted give this chicken a
purpose right your purpose little one
you are my mining buddy and we shall go
mining together this is your purpose
we're gonna be best birds while we go
and get some diamonds i haven't really
got a mine little chicken so we're gonna
go down to the mine together
i'm gonna do it
i'm gonna say it look at all these
chickens
oh this was the stupidest place i could
have possibly chosen
for a mine that was
that was your idea wasn't it okay well
i've always needed a way up here so
what we'll do a little chicken is we'll
just go mine straight down there it's
actually kind of cute having a little
friend that i could take with me come on
buddy let's go get some diamonds i have
a funny story
back in season six there was a certain
superhero on the block i.e poultry man
and my friend bigby stats he used to
call him mr cluck and i don't i don't
know where he got this name from because
mr cluck is nothing like poultry man so
you
are going to be mr cluck
come along mr cluck we've had zero luck
with diamonds so far plenty of luck with
lava though
[Music]
come on you
so after that mining session
it was pretty rough i'm not gonna not
gonna lie to you there's a long time of
mining and we only got 43 diamond ore
come on mr cluck
your use has been fulfilled as my
as my cave buddy
oh no no no no no
no oh
okay
well at least he served his purpose
right i forgot there's no slots
everywhere okay so we got 43 diamond
door where did all the chickens go oh no
they didn't despawn surely not all my
challenges
they're just hiding somewhere right oh
they could have gone so many places this
place isn't as covered as i thought oh
please
please tell me i haven't lost all my
chickens before i've even done the
challenges
i think an awful lot of the chickens
have vanished or they've got themselves
hidden somewhere so basically every now
and again i'm just gonna come across a
chicken in this labyrinth and it's just
gonna give me a challenge
like this one give the treasure island
another go re i said never again i said
literally
never again i just got some diamonds
back in fact we should see how lucky we
are with this no right let's see if we
get
lucky
hopefully not a bad amount a stack and a
half just for context by the way i spent
nine of these on the treasure island
game and he wants me to do it again
one more spoon
one
that is all we're doing it's pretty much
all i can afford as well at least it's
got a decent durability this one right
this is it
the the only shovel i'm buying
there it is
finally
so
no messing around
we're just gonna we're just gonna get
this over and done with so to maximize
efficiency if we do this in a some kind
of pattern if i go down here nothing one
two
nothing
oh i know exactly where this is going
one two
oh
nothing oh
no way
holy
mother of jackpot
yes yes mega omega mega awesome omega
oh my goodness
that is three times the amount i just
spent mining
yo
we had the mega jack
leave we're leaving we're leaving before
scout takes any more of our diamonds
oh oh
oh i'm shaking that is a lot of diamonds
i also saw someone say on i think i
think reddit that there's a block of
gravel
here and they think that iskall's hidden
something here personally i think not
but we never know well it broke anyway
if any other hermit wants to continue
this
they feel feel free because i
am
so done with this mini game
so done with this mini game i think
we've got to turn this into diamonds
we got we got to put this back into
blocks
i know i know for a fact we're not going
to get where we once were
but this is gonna this is gonna put a
dent back in it for sure
that kind of goes to show
just how unlucky or lucky you can be on
that game that was one shovel and we hit
jackpot and i bought maybe 18 shovels
before and got next to nothing
oh my goodness
i think because this was barge funds we
got to tower this up from the barge
oh my goodness
it took me a while to get up here that's
how many diamonds we got
right here we go bear in mind we already
had two stacks there was already a stack
of diamonds in there so from these all
alone we are looking
at a potential
diamond load
there we go
oh
that feels good
that feels good so
from that we got one two three four five
six
uh we got five and a bit stacks of
diamonds plus the two from earlier oh my
oh my let's put these in blocks
52 blocks we still made a loss on this
whole thing but i don't care i'm so
excited
that is looking a lot healthier
than it was
wow we spent this whole episode pretty
much just trying to make our diamonds
back from where we started
but i feel like
we've achieved that we did some work on
the upside down we continued the
mycelium resistance we added some barge
boxes and we've been challenged to a
plethora of poultry related hermit
challenges it is getting
quite mad on the hermitcraft server and
next episode we're going to go and get
through some of those chickens
so with that being said thank you very
much for watching i hope you've enjoyed
this episode and i shall see you
in the next one good bye